<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>3: Strings &amp; memory on Getting Started with Programming in Rust</title><link>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/</link><description>Recent content in 3: Strings &amp; memory on Getting Started with Programming in Rust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Creating a string variable in Rust</title><link>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/create-string/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/create-string/</guid><description>Rust has two kinds of string types: strings and string slices, the primary difference being their mutability; a mutable variable can be changed, whereas an immutable variable cannot be changed.
Name Type Mutability A string String Can be mutable or immutable A string slice &amp;amp;str Is only immutable Think of a string like a vector; it can grow and shrink, you can push and pop elements into and out of it, and it is automatically freed when it goes out of scope.</description></item><item><title>Return a string from a function</title><link>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/return-string-from-function/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/return-string-from-function/</guid><description>Recall that there are two types of strings in Rust: there&amp;rsquo;s the vector-esque String, and the string slice &amp;amp;str. We use a String when we want a string that we can modify like we would an array (pushing and popping characters and/or strings to and from it), and &amp;amp;str when we only need a slice of an existing string.
We can modify get_version() to return a string by modifying the return value of the function.</description></item><item><title>Chapter 3 Checkpoint</title><link>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/checkpoint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jesselawson.github.io/getting-started-with-rust/chapter3/checkpoint/</guid><description>In this chapter, we got really familiar with how Rust deals with strings in memory. Next, we&amp;rsquo;ll begin parsing command line arguments and start working with the filesystem.
🚀 Third Checkpoint Reached! 🚀 "It&amp;#39;s not that I&amp;#39;m so smart, it&amp;#39;s just that I stay with problems longer." &amp;mdash;Albert Einstein Before continuing, you should be able to confidently:
All our code up to this point is available here on GitHub.
You may also wish to go back and review the third chapter.</description></item></channel></rss>